Andrew Capp

Los Angeles Metropolitan Area, CA 91748 | 626-341-2421 | acapp909@gmail.com

Github: ACAPP-dev | LinkedIn | Blog | Portfolio Website

SUMMARY

Full stack web developer with 30 years of experience in hospitality, leadership, accounting, and computer systems. Improved processes and developed tools to maximize efficiency and accuracy. Directed teams with focus on exceeding expectations. Transitioned to coding to follow passions for creating useful tools, learning, and helping people.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Ruby, Ruby on Rails, SQL, ActiveRecord, Javascript, Sinatra, Git, React, React-Redux, HTML / CSS, Bootstrap CSS, Excel/VBA. Omniauth Gem

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Stock Market Application - Github Repository | Demo Video

"View company data and stock chart, maintain company watchlists, view daily stock price data for user defined periods."

- Created using JavaScript, React, and Redux as well as utilizing Ruby on Rails and a SQLite database.
- Integrated a 3rd party library for stock charts and used an API for stock data.
- Devised an asynchronous function to perform multiple fetches and wrap results in an object.
- Utilized React Router to enable single page functionality with traditional HTTP addresses.

Andrew's Slot Machine - Github Repository | Demo Video

"Play a 'realistic' slot machine using your browser. This slot machine has much better odds than a traditional slot machine in Las Vegas. See how high you can get your balance."

- Developed application with Ruby on Rails MVC Framework and a SQLite database.
- Practiced using raw HTML and CSS to create the user interface.
- Utilized JavaScript to enable single page functionality and enhance user experience.

Auto Dealership Website - Github Repository | Demo Video

"Website to view an exotic car dealer's vehicle inventory and make sales or service appointments at that dealership."

- Implemented user security access levels for administrative functionality.
- Assembled HTML and Bootstrap CSS to design a robust user experience.
- Enabled Facebook login functionality with Omniauth Gem library.
- Coded back-end ActiveRecord functionality enabling vehicle search and sort capabilities.

EXPERIENCE

Hilton Hotels Multiple Locations 11/1988 - 09/2019

Director of Finance at Hilton Anaheim (1,574 rooms and \$124 million in annual revenue)

- Progressed from night auditor while in college to director of finance at one of the largest hotels on the West Coast.
- Provided reliable, consistent performance with no missed monthly financial closings for more than 26 years.
- Liaised with owners, corporate staff, lenders, and auditors; presented monthly financial results to owners.
- Participated in strategic planning, revenue management, risk management, and other leadership tasks.
- Oversaw monthly and annual forecasts including coordination of the team's effort to achieve accuracy goals.
- Prepared cash flow forecasts and owner distributions while ensuring adequate cash for millions in payments.
- Managed accounting staff of 20 plus purchasing staff of 15; reviewed work, coached as needed, trained new staff.

DK Systems Durango, CO 12/1987 - 11/1988

Sales Clerk & IT Support Technician

Worked with developers to customize Dbase applications for real estate clients.

Conducted sales calls and helped customers with technical issues.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School / University of California, Irvine

Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript program

California State University, San Bernardino

Master of Business Administration, Finance

Fort Lewis College

Bachelor of Arts, Accounting

Remote 10/2019 - 08/2020 San Bernardino, CA 12/2005 Durango, CO 04/1991